Linus Cheung



1020cheung@gmail.com



+18586509076



linkedin.com/in/linus-cheung-864a251aa

Summary

A diligent person who believes hard- work and critical thinking are the keystones to be successful in every aspect. Aiming to leverage my abilities from school, working experience, and critical thinking to land a knowledge expanding work environment. Excellent communication skills and comfortable working in a fast-paced, growthoriented work climate. Currently searching for a position that offers variety and the opportunity to forge both personally and professionally.

Experience



Freelance wedding Interpreter

Freelance

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Providing interpretation services for wedding events (English, Cantonese, Mandarin)

Marketing Project Assistant (Supply Chain)

Cycle Link (U.S.A.) Inc.

Nov 2022 - Aug 2023 (10 months)

- Monitored and analyzed project progress and communicated updates to the Project Manager
- Engaged in negotiating and finalizing contractual terms, demonstrating a strong acumen for cost reduction strategies to optimize project budgets
- ensure project success through efficient coordination and effective communication with all stakeholders

Project Coordinator (commodity trading)

WR Fibers, Inc. / Taison Group

Jan 2022 - Nov 2022 (11 months)

- -Serving as a media to accommodate supplier and client requests
- -Proposing favorable and cost-efficient export solutions to my client
- -Filing SI and AES for each purchase orders
- -Inputting each transaction key data into the SAP system for banking purposes
- -FSC certified, Processing FSC products with the coded sequences



Price Analyst

NEPTUNE SHIPPING LTD

Feb 2021 - Jan 2022 (1 year)

- -Liaised with both existing and Potential business Partners, and worked out import cooperation
- -Analyzed market price trends and resolved any issues regarding price change
- -Gave out quotations to our clients/consignees in regards to supply chain services
- -Served as an import/ Export agent and provide all-rounded support to our consignees

-Worked out different challenging import projects as a team leader

Marketing And Public Relations Assistant

LH Group Ltd (HKEx: 1978)

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019 (4 months)

- Provided creative ideas to promote and maintain a positive image for the company.
- -Fostered interconnected relationships with customers
- -Organized events to promote new stores and products
- Worked directly with clients regarding a joint promotion event

Quality Assurance Assistant

LH Group Ltd (HKEx: 1978)

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019 (4 months)

- Checked off a list of equipment and product that are imperative for safety
- Drafted reports regarding safety instructions of each store

Customer Service Officer

LHGroup

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018 (4 months)

- -Responsible for dealing with customer's dissatisfactions hence developed a set of skills to handle customer discomfort.
- -Rebuilt the connections for the company with dissatisfied customers
- Provided alternative solutions to customers on behalf of the company

Education



UC San Diego

Bachlor Degree, International Business

2016 - 2020

Vice President, UCSD Hong Kong student Union

- -Promoted the welfare of the Cantonese- speaking Chinese student body.
- -Collaborated with diverse groups from different universities such as USC, UCLA, UCSB, UCI, to hold various cultural events.
- -Provided a social environment for those who want to stay in touch with the Cantonese-speaking culture

Lancaster Mennonite School

High School Diploma



UC San Diego

Professional certificate, Computer Software Engineering

Skills

 ${\sf MongoDB} \ \bullet \ {\sf MySQL} \ \bullet \ {\sf Node.js} \ \bullet \ {\sf Express.js} \ \bullet \ {\sf HTML5} \ \bullet \ {\sf Cascading Style Sheets} \ ({\sf CSS}) \ \bullet \ {\sf JavaScript}$

• TypeScript • Diverse Groups • Marketing